<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OutReach on I, Oliver Bonham-Carter, In June</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/outreach/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OutReach on I, Oliver Bonham-Carter, In June</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Oliver Bonham-Carter</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 22:05:15 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/outreach/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>5. Machine Learning Basics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/outreach/5_ml_basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 22:05:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/outreach/5_ml_basics/</guid>
      <description>Today we are talking about Machine Learning, or the notion that data can be used to teach a computer to recognize types of patterns. Incredible as it may seem computers, like you, can also learn to do amazing things!&#xA;Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about how machine learning works (in a very general sense)! Let&amp;rsquo;s first put ourselves in the place of the learner.&#xA;Patterns Observed by Humans: Film Posters Imagine that the below posters are for films that you might go to see.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4. T Tests</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/outreach/4_t-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 09:25:25 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/outreach/4_t-tests/</guid>
      <description>Determining the difference between the means of two data sets. How would you determine the difference between the averages following two datasets? We show a scatter plot and a histogram plot for each group (i.e., 1 and 2). Are these plots enough to determine a likeness between the plots?&#xA;But first, let&amp;rsquo;s get into a Jupyter client where we can run Python code.&#xA;&amp;#x200B; The Data How could you differentiate the two data sets shown below?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3. Cool Plots</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/outreach/3_coolplots/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 23:43:43 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/outreach/3_coolplots/</guid>
      <description>Here we spend some time to look at plots which are not like the traditional plots that we have seen before. Below are different ways to use graphics to explore data and describe trends to show patterns.&#xA;But first, let&amp;rsquo;s get into a Jupyter client where we can run Python code.&#xA;The Koch Snowflake (a fractle) &amp;#x200B; import matplotlib.pyplot as plt import numpy as np def koch_snowflake(order, scale=10): &amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34; Return two lists x, y of point coordinates of the Koch snowflake.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2. Plotting and Distributions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/outreach/2_plotting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 23:40:01 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/outreach/2_plotting/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#x200B; &amp;#x200B; We will spend a moment to study different ways of visually describing data using plots. Here we will develope some Python programming techniques to create some data to be used for plotting. In specific, we will look at several types of plots and then decide what types of features each plot has and how it could be helpful when describing data.&#xA;But first, let&amp;rsquo;s get into a Jupyter client where we can run Python code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1. Intro to Python</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/outreach/1_pythonintro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 19:09:12 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/outreach/1_pythonintro/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#x200B; &amp;#x200B; We will spend a moment to familiarize ourselves with Python3. Once you know some of the basics to this powerful programming language, you will be able to complete amazing tasks and perform astounding feasts of programming!&#xA;You are invited to help yourself to the below links to learn about Python. Be sure to ask questions when necessary! &amp;#x1f603;&#xA;&amp;#x200B; &amp;#x200B; Python Programming Resources&#xA;Play with code from W3&amp;rsquo;s super Python Tutorial</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Online Resources</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/outreach/0_onlineresources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 21:30:44 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/outreach/0_onlineresources/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#x200B; Welcome! Here, you will find a list of interactive Data Analytics resources. Come play with data without having to write a line of code!&#xA;Music&#xA;How Music Taste Evolved How Billboard’s Top Hits Changed Largest Vocabulary in Hip Hop Interactive Info Visualization of Spotify Music Genre Overtime Exploratory Data Analysis of Various Music Datasets Library&#xA;New York Public Library Ney York Public Library Collection NYPL’s Public Domain Library Mixed ideas</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
