<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on I, Oliver Bonham-Carter, In June</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on I, Oliver Bonham-Carter, In June</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Oliver Bonham-Carter</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 23:52:09 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Infomaid</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/infomaid/infomaid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 23:52:09 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/infomaid/infomaid/</guid>
      <description>A Textual AI and RAG-Enabled Learning Application A simple textual AI RAG application using Ollama for generative AI, chatting with PDFs AND chatting (querying) documents prepared in xml!&#xA;GitHub link: https://github.com/developmentAC/infomaid&#xA;Overview Infomaid is a simple AI prompt-based solution with built in Retrieval augmented generation (RAG) support!&#xA;Welcome to this simple AI application! Infomaid is an experimental AI prompt-driven solution (i.e., each &amp;ldquo;chat&amp;rdquo; involves writing a separate prompt to use with a new execution of Infomaid) to help complete text-based work with information.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gradealert</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/gradealert/gradealert/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 22:17:24 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/gradealert/gradealert/</guid>
      <description>GitHub link: https://github.com/developmentAC/gradeAlert&#xA;Table of contents Overview Tool Usage At Terminal CSV Outputted files Placing Gradebook Files Pushing in Bulk File Structure Summary of Commands A Work In Progress Overview GitHub Classroom is an excellent resource to handle work repositories for a course of many students. Each student, after &amp;ldquo;accepting&amp;rdquo; an assignment is issued a unique repository in which work can be completed and pushed to the instructor.&#xA;Here, we suggest that GitHub Classroom be used to report grades to each student who has a grade book &amp;ldquo;assignment&amp;rdquo; repository.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sentiminer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/sentiminer/sentiminer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 21:05:25 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/sentiminer/sentiminer/</guid>
      <description>GitHub link: https://github.com/developmentAC/sentiminer&#xA;Table of contents Overview Mechanism Commands Output References Evolution Overview Sentiment analysis is the semantic study of emotion in language. This form of analysis is used to determine the level of satisfaction or dissatisfaction in textual data such as reviews, survey responses, online and social media posting and similar. Due to the often high volume of feedback from the above types of textual data, sentiment analysis provides an automated solution for determining the &amp;ldquo;feeling&amp;rdquo; of the text.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/infomaid/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/infomaid/readme/</guid>
      <description>Infomaid: An AI and RAG-Enabled Learning Application Date: 4 June 2024&#xA;Oliver Bonham-Carter&#xA;Email: obonhamcarter at allegheny.edu&#xA;Contents Overview Prerequisites Set Up Local Models for Ollama Setting Up The Project Execution Parameters Generation Output Working with PDF Data Sample Project Testing the Code Ethical Note A Work In Progress Overview Infomaid is a simple AI prompt-based solution with built in Retrieval augmented generation (RAG) support!&#xA;Welcome to this simple AI application!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
