<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio on I, Oliver Bonham-Carter, In June</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Portfolio on I, Oliver Bonham-Carter, In June</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Oliver Bonham-Carter</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 19:47:09 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Faculty Talk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/sample-project/index_facultytalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 19:47:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/sample-project/index_facultytalk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is necessary to update the pedagogy in CS to produce computer scientists who are able to think holistically in the design and development of novel technologies which cater to more humanitarian interests. Allegheny’s Department of Computer Science, working in tandem with other schools and partners, aims to develop and integrate responsible thinking into the curricula and the technical aspects of its CS courses. This serves to inspire students, and results in the creation of open source projects, activities, programs and associated media in which responsible thinking plays a larger role in the technology. In this talk, I will discuss these issues, in addition to identifying specific approaches and lessons-learned in this effort by our department.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GenExSt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/sample-project/index_genexst/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 19:47:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/sample-project/index_genexst/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interaction between genes is one driving force that can influence a biological outcome. In a genetic disease such as cancer, understanding genetic interactions may help us elucidate mechanisms sustaining cancer growth. A computational approach is one way to detect genetic interactions in the context of cancer. In this article, we introduce a tool, GenExSt, and its underlying method to study gene interactions. We applied our method to discover gene-pairs whose expressions demonstrate patterns of correlation. For this demonstration, we selected ten breast cancer gene expression data sets from the Genomic Data Commons Data Portal through National Cancer Institute. We focused on genes that suppress genome instability, or instability suppressing genes (GIS), many of which play an important role in cancer. We applied our method to an inter-comparison across data sets. Here we tested statistical normalization approaches derived from the combined expressions of randomly selected, single, housekeeping (HK) genes, and from the calculated mean of three expressions. In addition, our method derives R2 values from linear models in which the expressions of all possible pairs of GIS genes are placed in a linear model to produce heatmaps to indicate probable correlations. We show that results from our method are suited to normalized data, extracted from multiple genes simultaneously, rather than using single gene expression values. GenExSt may be used to study gene expression data in other settings provided that the concept of gene interactions is appropriate in the context.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BeagleTM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/sample-project/index_beagletm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 19:47:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/sample-project/index_beagletm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Investigators in bioinformatics are often confronted with the difficult task of connecting ideas, which are found scattered around the literature, using robust keyword searches. It is often customary to identify only a few keywords in a research article to facilitate search algorithms, which is usually completed in absence of a general approach that would serve to index all possible keywords of an article’s characteristic attributes. Based on only a hand-full of keywords, articles are therefore prioritized by search algorithms that point investigators to seeming subsets of their knowledge. In addition, many articles escape algorithm search strategies due to the fact that their keywords were vague, or have become unfashionable terms. In this case, the article, as well as its source of knowledge, may be lost to the community. Owing to the growing size of the literature, we introduce a text mining method and tool, (BeagleTM), for knowledge harvesting from papers in a literature corpus without the use of article meta-data. Unlike other text mining tools that only highlight found keywords in articles, our method allows users to visually ascertain which keywords have been featured in studies together with others in peer-reviewed work. Drawing from an arbitrarily-sized corpus, BeagleTM creates visual networks describing interrelationships between user-defined terms to facilitate the discovery of connected or parallel studies. We report the effectiveness of BeagleTM by illustrating its ability to connect the keywords from types of PTMs (post-translational modifications), stress-factors, and disorders together according to their relationships. These relationships facilitate the discovery of connected studies, which is often challenging to determine due to the frequently unrelated keywords that were tied to relevant articles containing this type of information.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Thesis Work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/sample-project/index_thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 19:47:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/sample-project/index_thesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After synthesis, a protein is still immature until it has been customized for a specific task. Post-translational modifications (PTMs) are steps in biosynthesis to perform this customization of protein for unique functionalities. PTMs are also important to protein survival because they rapidly enable protein adaptation to environmental stress factors by conformation change. The overarching contribution of this thesis is the construction of a computational profiling framework for the study of biological signals stemming from PTMs associated with stressed proteins. In particular, this work has been developed to predict and detect the biological mechanisms involved in types of stress response with PTMs in mitochondrial (Mt) and non-Mt protein.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
